# SAURABH SHARMA

• Canada (Open to relocation) • +1 (514) 660-4529 • saurabhsharma.can@gmail.com

#### SUMMARY

Recent M. Eng. Software Engineering graduate from Concordia University, Montreal. Have over three years of experience in Information Technology as a Security Researcher at Quick Heal Technologies and 8 months of Canadian experience as a Data Migration Specialist at Randstad Canada.

Core Skills: Collaboration, Organization, Teamwork, Consistency, Analytical, Conflict Resolution, Empathy

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Randstad Canada (contracted to Groupe Lemur Inc (Le))

Montreal, Canada

**Data Migration Specialist** 

Apr 2023 - Nov 2023

- · Extracted data from a legacy ERP system and imported 35K customer/item records into Oracle NetSuite.
- · Implemented robust data cleansing, deduplication, missing data handling, error correction, and formatting to ensure a consistent data structure.
- Designed dashboards and reports using Power BI to visualize trends and support business decision-making.
- Created NetSuite templates for importing data into NetSuite.
- Tech Stack: Excel. Power BI. Oracle NetSuite. ETL. GitHub. Microsoft Access.

Quick Heal Technologies Security Researcher

Pune, India

Apr 2020 – Aug 2022

- As a Security Researcher and developer in the Host Intrusion and Prevention Systems (HIPS) team, I worked on the following tasks:

- · Created Power BI / Kibana dashboards to visualize top detection performances across various metrics and generated reports for higher management.
- · Developed Python scripts to regularly integrate emerging threats public rules with the Quick Heal detection signatures database.
- Monitored detection telemetry data regularly and initiated proactive actions to fix false positives, covering 100% customer cases.
- Built **Python and BAT scripts** to automate tasks within the team, improving overall workflow efficiency.
- · Executed API testing using Postman and SOAP UI, verifying the reliability and accuracy of signature tracking server responses.
- · Analysed and reverse-engineered OLE files to identify hidden malicious code and phishing URLs, added over 2200 detections.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams on 5+ projects, improving team efficiency and project outcomes by 20%.
- Conducted knowledge transfer sessions for new QH members, ensuring a solid understanding of detection techniques and automation scripts.
- Tech Stack: Power BI, Python, SQL, Power Query, DAX, ETL, Postman, Wireshark, Fiddler, ELK Stack, Splunk, Presto, AWS Athena & S3, Pandas, Suricata, Snort, GitHub, CI/CD, Data Analysis, SAP, MS Suite, Jira, Confluence.

Quick Heal Technologies Pune, India

#### Research and Development (Intern)

Apr 2019 – Mar 2020

· Acquired foundational knowledge in AWS (S3, EC2, and Athena) for scalable software solutions and system integration.

- Gained proficiency in various network protocols like HTTP, TCP, UDP, and OLE file structures (DOCX, PDF, RTF, XLS).
- · Researched technical papers to understand the latest techniques for enhancing the quality of the detection signatures.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Data Analysis and Statistics: Power BI, Tableau, Apache Spark, Pandas, Power Query, DAX

Programming: Java, Python, SQL, JavaScript, PL/SQL

Database: Microsoft SQL Server, SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Cloud Technologies: Microsoft Azure, AWS, Snowflake

Software Engineering Practices: SDLC, Agile Methodologies, Test-Driven Development (TDD), CI/CD

Version Control & Project Management: Git, SVN, JIRA, Confluence

Competencies: Data Analysis, ETL, Data Migration, REST APIs, Presto, ELK stack, MS Suite, Linux, macOS, Windows

## **EDUCATION**

#### CONCORDIA UNIVERSITY

Master of Engineering (Software Engineering)

Montreal, Canada

Sep 2022 – Jun 2024

CHITKARA UNIVERSITY

**Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Science)** 

Chandigarh, India Aug 2016 - Jun 2020

# ACADEMIC PROJECTS

## Roboprof Chatbot | Python, RDF, Apache Fuseki, SPARQL, Knowledge base, Rasa

Jan 2024 – Apr 2024

- An Intelligent agent for university and student inquiries using Knowledge Graphs and NLP.
- Created a Knowledge Base using RDFLib in turtle Format and populated it with an open dataset.
- Integrated Rasa with Hugging Face into Roboprof, enhancing the system's conversational abilities.

## Jobseekr- A job application portal | ReactJS, NodeJS, Firebase, GitHub

Jun 2023 – Jul 2023

• Developed "Jobseekr", an online job application portal for candidates and recruiters by using ReactJS, NodeJS, Firebase, and GitHub.

### Cohort Watch, Quick Heal Technologies

Feb 2022 - Mar 2022

· Worked on a project employing the ELK stack and Suricata IDS to identify anomalies in system network traffic.

• Crafted a Kibana dashboard for visualizing system anomaly data, facilitating thorough analysis.

Checkout my GitHub for more projects: www.github.com/saurabhs679

Communication Skills: English (Fluent), Hindi (Native), Punjabi (Intermediate)

LinkedIn- https://www.linkedin.com/in/saurabh-sharma1/